A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Arts and Humanities Program Files, Marcia T. Thompson FA1482
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Symphony Orchestra Program (SOP), 1953-1988; 2
  - Symphony and Orchestra Program #1 - 1-10 - KH, 1972-1986 (Box 20, Folder 186)
    5. Boston Symphony
    6. Brooklyn Philharmonic
    7. Buffalo Philharmonic
    8. Chicago Symphony
    9. Cincinnati Symphony
    10. Cleveland Symphony
  - Symphony and Orchestra Program #1 - 11-20 - KH, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 187)
    11. Columbus Symphony Orchestra
    12. Dallas Symphony
    13. Denver Symphony
    14. Detroit Symphony
    15. Festival Casals
    16. Festiva Orchestra
    17. Florida Symphony
    18. Fort Wayne Philharmonic
    19. Hartford Symphony
    20. Honolulu Symphony
  - Symphony and Orchestra Program #1 - 21-29 - KH, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 188)
    21. Houston Symphony
    22. Hudson Valley Philharmonic
    23. Indianapolis Symphony
    24. Jacksonville Symphony
    25. Kalamazoo Symphony
    26. Kansas City Philharmonic
    27.Little Orchestra
    28. Los Angeles Philharmonic
    29. Louisville Philharmonic
  - Symphony and Orchestra Program #2 - 30-39 - KH, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 189)
    30. Memphis Orchestral
    31. Milwaukee Symphony
    32. Minnesota Orchestra
    33. Nashville Symphony
    34. National Symphony
    35. New Haven Symphony Orchestra
    36. New Jersey Symphony
    37. New Orleans Symphony
    38. New York Philharmonic
    39. North Carolina Symphony
  - Symphony and Orchestra Program #2 - 40-49 - KH, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 190)
    40. Oakland Symphony Orchestra
    41. Oklahoma City Symphony
    42. Omaha Civic Music Association
    43. Philadelphia Orchestra
    44. Phoenix Symphony Orchestra
    45. Pittsburgh Symphony
    46. Oregon Symphony
    47. Rhode Island Philharmonic
    48. Richmond Symphony
    49. Rochester Philharmonic
  - Symphony and Orchestra Program #2 - 50-61 - KH, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 191)
    50. Sacramento Philharmonic
    51. San Antonio Symphony
    52. San Diego Symphony
    53. San Francisco Symphony
    54. Seattle Symphony
    55. Shreveport Symphony
    56. St. Louis Symphony
    57. Syracuse Symphony
    58. Toldeo Orchestra
    59. Tulsa Philharmonic
    60. Utah Symphony
    61. Wichita Symphony
  - Symphony Orchestra Program - Workbook - Book I (A-F), 1962-1972 (Box 21, Folder 192)
    Review Memos Chart
    Summary of SOP Maintenance Problems
    American Symphony Orchestra
    Baltimore Symphony Orchestra Association
    Birmingham Symphony Association
    Boston Symphony Orchestra
    Brooklyn Philharmonia, Inc.
    Buffalo Philharmonic Orchestra Society, Inc.
    Chicago Symphony Orchestra
    Cincinnati Symphony Orchestra
    Columbus Symphony Orchestra
    Dallas Symphony Association
    Denver Symphony
    Detroit Symphony Orchestra
    Festival Orchestra Society
    Florida Symphony Orchestra
  - Symphony Orchestra Program - Workbook - Book II (H-M), 1967-1972 (Box 21, Folder 193)
    Symphony Society of Greater Hartford, Inc.
    Honolulu Symphony Society
    Houston Symphony Society
    Indiana State Symphony Orchestra
    Jacksonville Symphony Association
    Kalamazoo Symphony Society
    Little Orchestra Society
    Southern California Symphony - Hollywood Bowl Association
    Louisville Philharmonic Society
    Memphis Orchestral Society, Inc.
    Milwaukee Symphony Orchestra, Inc.
    Minnesota Orchestral Association
  - Symphony Orchestra Program - Workbook - Book III (N-R), 1971-1972 (Box 22, Folder 194)
    Nashville Symphony Orchestra
    National Symphony Orchestra Association
    New Jersey Symphony Orchestra
    New Haven Symphony Orchestra
    New Orleans Philharmonic Orchestra
    The Philharmonic-Symphony Society of New York, Inc.
    North Carolina Symphony Society, Inc.
    Oakland Symphony Orchestra Association
    Oklahoma City Symphony Society
    Omaha Symphony Association
    Oregon Symphony Society
    Philadelphia Orcherstra Association
    Phoenix Symphony Association
    Pittsburgh Symphony Society
    Richmond Symphony, Inc.
    Rhode Island Philharmonic Orchestra
    Rochester Civic Music Association, Inc.
  - Symphony Orchestra Program - Workbook - Book IV (S-Z), 1971-1972 (Box 22, Folder 195)
    Sacramento Symphony Association
    St. Louis Symphony Society
    Symphony Society of San Antonio
    San Diego Symphony Orchestra Association
    San Francisco Symphony Association
    Seattle Symphony Orchestra, Inc.
    Shreveport Symphony Society
    Syracuse Symphony Society, Inc.
    Toledo Orchestra Association
    Tulsa Philharmonic Society, Inc.
    Utah Symphony Society
    Wichita Symphony Society
  - Symphony Orchestra Program Review 1 - A-B - Handwritten Worksheets, 1973-1977 (Box 22, Folder 196)
    American Symphony
    Atlanta Arts Alliance, Inc.
    Baltimore Symphony Orchestra, Inc.
    Boston Symphony
    Buffalo Philharmonic Orchestra
  - Symphony Orchestra Program Review 2 - C - Handwritten Worksheets, 1974-1976 (Box 22, Folder 197)
    Chicago Symphony
    Cleveland Orchestra
  - Symphony Orchestra Program Review 3 - D - Handwritten Worksheets, 1974-1976 (Box 22, Folder 198)
    Dallas Symphony Association, Inc.
    Denver Symphony Association
    Detroit Symphony Orchestra, Inc.
  - Symphony Orchestra Program Review 4 - E-H - Handwritten Worksheets, 1972-1976 (Box 23, Folder 199)
    Include:
    Florida Symphony
    Fort Wayne Philharmonic
    Hartford Symphony
    Houston Symphony
    Hudson Valley Philharmonic
  - Symphony Orchestra Program Review 5 - I-L - Handwritten Worksheets, 1972-1976 (Box 23, Folder 200)
    Indianapolis Symphony
    Jacksonville Symphony
    Little Orchestra Society, Inc.
    Los Angeles Philharmonic/Southern California Symphony-Hollywood Bowl Association
    Louisville Philharmonic
  - Symphony Orchestra Program Review 6 - M-N - Handwritten Worksheets, 1973-1980 (Box 23, Folder 201)
    Memphis Orchestral Society
    Nashville Symphony Association
    National Symphony Orchestra
  - Symphony Orchestra Program Review 7 - N - Handwritten Worksheets, 1973-1980 (Box 23, Folder 202)
    National Symphony Orchestra Association of Washington, D.C.
    New Haven Symphony Orchestra, Inc.
    The Philharmonic-Symphony Society New York, Inc.
  - Symphony Orchestra Program Review 8 - O - Handwritten Worksheets, 1975-1977 (Box 24, Folder 203)
  - Symphony Orchestra Program Review 9 - P-R - Handwritten Worksheets, 1975-1977 (Box 24, Folder 204)
    The Philadelphia Orchestra Association
    The Richmond Symphony
    Rochester Philharmonic Orchestra, Inc.
  - Symphony Orchestra Program Review 10 - S - Handwritten Worksheets, 1973-1978 (Box 24, Folder 205)
    San Antonio Symphony Society
    San Diego Symphony
    Seattle Symphony
  - Symphony Orchestra Program Review 11 - S-Z - Handwritten Worksheets, 1973-1980 (Box 24, Folder 206)
    Syracuse Symphony Orchestra, Inc.
    Toledo Orchestra Association, Inc.
    Wichita Symphony Society, Inc.
  - Symphony Orchestra Program - Discussion Papers - Binder 1 (2 folders), 1964-1966 (Box 25, Folder 207-208)
    Papers include:
    Humanities and the Arts Program Planning Budget - Information Paper - June 1964
    Discussion Paper Program for Symphony Orchestras - September 8, 1964 (blue cover sheet)
    Discussion Paper Program for Symphony Orchestras - September 24-25, 1964 (yellow cover)
    Program Planning Budget Request for Fiscal 1966-1976-1968 - June 1965 - Information Paper
    Board of Trustees Docket - September 30-Oct. 1, 1965
    Request for Grants out of Appropriation - May 27, 1966
    Also includes orchestra budget overview documents (appendices), theater companies financial data, ballet companies financial data, civic operas financial data, and major opera companies financial data
    The Ford Foundation, September 30-October 1, 1965 Meeting, Part III Humanities and the Arts, Board of Trustees Docket
  - Symphony Orchestra Program - Discussion Papers - Binder 2, 1964-1972 (Box 25, Folder 209)
    Program Planning Budget - June 1964 - Information Paper
    Discussion Paper - September 8, 1964 (blue cover sheet)
    Discussion Paper - September 24-25, 1964 (yellow cover)
    Program Planning Budget - June 1965 - Information Paper
    Trust Committee Meeting - April 20, 1972
  - Symphony Orchestra Program - Background, 1966-1985 (Box 25, Folder 210)
    1. Notes: Overview and Essential Elements of Program
    2. SOP Grantees - List of Grantees from 1966 Press Release
    3. Major Orchestras: List of Major Orchestras, Tentative Allocations, Pre-Grant Questionnaire Covering Letter and Mailing List
    4. Metropolitans: List of Metropolitan Orchestras, Tentative Allocations, Affirmative Action (Women) Tally, ASOL Classifications, Pre-Grant Questionnaire Covering Letter and Mailing List
    5. Borderline Cases: Discussion Status Report, March 3, 1966
    6. Terms and Matching: Notes and Memoranda
    7. Questionnaire: Tally of Three Pre-Grant Questionnaire, by Orchestra Sample Questionnaires, 4/27/65, 11/3/65, 4/12/66
    8. Disposability Letter 6/1/72: Sample letter regarding treatment of net realized capital gains
    9. Reallocation Letter 9/1/72: Sample letter regarding redistribution of trust with mailing list
    10. Letter Report 2/1/73 - FF Letter including "Symphonic Strains (Financial)"
    11. Statistics: Wages, allocations, union negotiations notes, operating data 1970-1981
  - Symphony Orchestra Program - Yearly Evaluations, 1971-1984 (Box 25, Folder 211)
    1. Post-1976 SOP Evaluation - Memo, Thompson to Kennedy, 1977 - "Symphony Orchestras: Then vs. Now and the Future"; FF Letter, 1973 - "Symphonic Strains (Financial)"
    2. 1975 SOP Evaluation - Review Memorandum, 1975; Memo LRV to MATT suggesting graphic displays, 1975
    3. 1974 SOP Evaluation - Changes in Budget Level Groupings, 1974
    4. 1973 SOP Evaluation - Orchestras Ranked by Expenses 1973, 72, 71; Changes in Budget Level Groupings, 1973
    5. 1972 SOP Evaluation - Review Memorandum, 1972; Orchestras Ranked by Expenses, 1971 and 72; Changes in Budget Level Groupings, 1972; Percentage Matching Achieved by orchestram 1972; Memo LRV to MATT, 1973, "Most Frequent Worksheet Review Points"
    6. 1971 SOP Evaluation - Table I Orchestras Ranked by Per Cent of Matching Achieved, Table II Orchestras Ranked by Total Expenses, 1971, Table II Orchestras Ranked by Endowment, Table IV Cost vs. Market Value of Matching Fund Assets, 1971, Table V Analysis of Total Expense for Nine Years, 1962-1971, Table VI Net Current Position by Orchestra 1971
  - Symphony Orchestra Program - Trust Distribution - Final Grant Status Reports, 1966-1980 (Box 26, Folder 212)
  - Symphony Orchestra Program - Deferred Income Analysis, 1972-1985 (Box 26, Folder 213)
  - Symphony Orchestra Program - Evaluation of Developmental Funds A-Z, 1967-1985 (Box 26, Folder 214)
    1. Summary Evaluation Memorandum, Oleg Lobanov, 1972
    2. Evaluation Memoranda for Developmental Grants, by Orchestra, with Attachments: Utilization of Developmental Funds 1967-71
  - Symphony Orchestra Program - Summary of Transactions A-Z, 1966-1980 (Box 26, Folder 215)
  - Symphony Orchestra Program - Post-1976 Review Material, 1966-1987 (Box 26, Folder 216)
  - Symphony Orchestra Program - Summary Worksheets for 1976 Review, 1965-1985 (Box 26, Folder 217)
    1. Grants Summary - Grants Listed by Amount of Matching Requited Grant Amounts, Original and Modified, by Orchestra Developmental Fund Payments
    2. Matching Achieved - "Table I" - Orchestras Ranked by Per Cent of Matching Achieved, Percentage Matching Achieved, by Orchestra, 1972, Final
    3. Matching Fund Fair Market Value - By Orchestra, 1971-1976, Matching Funds Accounts Breakdown (Stock, Bonds, Comm. Paper, Other)
    4. Endowment Intentions - Summary of Responses by Orchestra
    5. Other Endowments Funds at Book Value - By Orchestra, 1971-76
    6. Endowment/Investment Income - By Orchestra, 1965, 75
    7. Matching Fund Rate of Return - By Group, No Figures for Individual Orchestras, 1975
    8. General Fund Balance - By Orchestra, 1972-1976
    9. Notes Payable - By Orchestra, 1975, 76
    10. Total Expenses - By Orchestra, 1965, 1971-76
    11. Rank by Total General Operating Expenses - Orchestras Ranked for 1965, 1971-76
    12. Earned Income - By Orchestra, In Dollars, 1972-1976
    13. Per Cent Earned Income/Total Expenses - By Orchestra, 1963-70 (incomplete), 1971-76; Rank Order, 1975, 76; Broadcast and Recording Income, by Orchestra, 1965, 75
    14. Earnings Gap - By Orchestra, 1972-1976
    15. Grants and Contributions, By Orchestra, 1972-1976
    16. Maintaining/Sustaining - Sustaining Funds (Required vs. Achieved), $ Raised and # Contributors
    17. Tax Support - By Orchestra, Analysis of Grants and Gifts Sources, 1965, 1973, 1975
    18. Net Income (Loss) - By Orchestra, 1971-76
    19. Multi-Year Forecast - By Orchestra, Info. on Long Range Plans
    20. Auditors - By Orchestra, 1971-1976
    21. Season and Wages - Contract Minimums, by Orchestra, 1976-77; Clippings re union negotiations; Weeks/Performances/Personnel, by Orchestra, 1966, 1975
  - Symphony Orchestra Program - Proposed Financing Plan - Meeting October 15, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 218)
    Notes and Memoranda: Proposed plan for Ford Foundation 50% participation in local loans to retire existing liabilities
  - Symphony Orchestra Program - Financial Worksheets for 1976 Review, 1972-1976 (Box 27, Folder 219)
    Index:
    1. Net Current Position Summary, 1976 (by orchestra)
    2. Net Working Capital (Deficiency), 1976 (27 orchestras only)
    3. Aggregate Net Current Position, 1972-1976
    4. Net Current Position, 1972-1976 (by budget group and orchestra)
    5. Current Assets, 1972-76 (by orchestra)
    6. Current Liabilities, 1972-76 (by orchestra)
    7. Summaries of Changes in Budget Levels, 1972-76
    8. Worksheets by Budget Level (data shown for each orchestra), 1972-76
  - Symphony Orchestra Program - Investment Plans and Responses to Questionnaire (4 folders), 1973 (Box 27, Folder 220-223)
    1. Notes and Memoranda Regarding Questionnaire
    2. Response, by orchestra, to "Attachment II" of August 1, 1973 letter
  - Symphony Orchestra Program - Long-Range Planning Responses, Orchestras A-Z (3 folders), 1975 (Box 27, Folder 224, Box 28, Folder 225-226)
    1. Response forms by orchestra - Long-Range Planning Checklist, Investment Breakdown of Endowment Funds - Stocks, Bonds, Commercial Paper, Other
- Cash Reserve Program, 1965-1987; 3
  The Cash Reserve Program was a Ford Foundation initiative that provided a series of non-renewable grants to civic opera companies and performing arts organizations in theater and dance. The program began in 1971 with a total of $8 million. The goal of the program was to alleviate the grantees' cash flow woes while preventing the grantee from becoming dependent on the Ford Foundation. If by the end of any given fiscal year the grantee had not produced sufficient income, earned and contributed, to meet all operating expenses and thus to replace its withdrawals from the cash reserve fund, it would mean that the grantee had been dependent on the Foundation for operating support and would be excluded from further participation in the program. If the grantee met all of the conditions of the grant and remained in the program for four years, then it would end up with no net current liabilities and a cash reserve.
  - Cash Reserve Program - Arts and the Ford Foundation (2 folders), 1975-1981 (Box 28, Folder 227-228)
  - Default: Grant Rescinded - Cash Reserve Program, 1971-1982 (Box 28, Folder 229)
  - Cash Reserve Program - Reports, 1972-1982 (Box 28, Folder 230)
    Education and Culture Committee: A Supplement to Part II Results, March 1982
    The Stabilization Strategy: An Interim Report, 1972-1980
    Mellon Symphony Orchestra Program: An Interim Report, 1977-1980
  - Interim Assessment of the Cash Reserve Program Grants to Selected Professional Performing Arts Organizations - Draft, Donald McDonagh (2 folders), 1978 (Box 28, Folder 231-232)
  - Humanities and the Arts Division: Cash Reserve Program - Trustees Subcommittee Meeting, 1971 September 15 (Box 28, Folder 233)
  - Cash Reserve Program - Nonrenewable Grants Program (2 folders), 1970-1971 (Box 28, Folder 234, Box 29, Folder 235)
  - Cash Reserve Grants - Background (1972 to date), 1971-1974 (Box 29, Folder 236)
  - Cash Reserve Program Grants, 1971-1980 (Box 29, Folder 237)
  - Cash Reserve - National Arts Stabilization Fund (NASF), Early Payees, Board Development (2 folders), 1982-1984 (Box 29, Folder 238-239)
  - Evaluation - Status Reports - Program for Administrative Interns and Museum Curatorial Training Program, 1977 May-June (Box 29, Folder 240)
  - Evaluation - Default: In Final Year Only - Cash Reserve Program, 1971-1975 (Box 29, Folder 241)
    Springfield Theatre Arts Association, Ballet West, Kansas City Lyric Theater, New Orleans House Association, Houston Grand Opera Association, Inc., American Ballet Theatre (Ballet Theatre Foundation), Kansas City Lyric Theater, Opera Festival Association (Lake George Opera Festival)
  - Evaluation - Default: In Final Year + One Earlier - Cash Reserve Program, 1971-1979 (Box 29, Folder 242)
    Dance Theatre Foundation, The Boston Ballet, Opera Company of Boston
  - Evaluation - Default: Interim Only and Modified - Cash Reserve Program, 1970-1980 (Box 29, Folder 243)
    Center Stage Associates, Western Opera Theater
  - Evaluation - Swing Year Grantees and Provisions - Cash Reserve Program, 1971-1976 (Box 29, Folder 244)
    Asolo State Theater
  - Cash Reserve Evaluation: Geographic Distribution - Dance,Theater, and Opera Programs, 1976-1978 (Box 29, Folder 245)
  - Evaluation - Extension History, 1975-1979 (Box 29, Folder 246)
  - Evaluation - Exchange with RGIC, 1977-1978 (Box 29, Folder 247)
  - Cash Reserve Grants - Background, 1972-1980 (Box 29, Folder 248)
  - Cash Reserve Grants - Background, 1971-1980 (Box 30, Folder 249)
  - Cash Reserve Statistics and Analysis - Binder 1, 1970-1977 (Box 30, Folder 250)
    Net Current POS
    Long-Term Liability
    Cash Reserve Balance
    General Operating Expenses
    Earned Income
    Earnings Gap
    Grants and Gifts
    General Operating Income
    Net Income (Loss)
  - Cash Reserve Statistics and Analysis - Binder 2 (2 folders), 1975-1977 (Box 30, Folder 251-252)
    Summary Analysis
    (Empty sections) Endowment Funds, Plant Fund, Deferred Income Analysis, General Operation Expenses, Earned Income, Earning Gap, Grants and Gifts, Net Income (Loss), Summaries
    Net Current Position
    Cash Reserve Fund
    General Operation Income
    Net Current Assets
    Working Capital (Cash) Reserve
    Working Capital Reserve
  - Cash Reserve Statistics and Analysis - Binder 3, 1975-1977 (Box 30, Folder 253)
  - Cash Reserve Statistics and Analysis - Binder 4, 1971-1981 (Box 30, Folder 254)
  - Stabilization (Cash Reserve Program) Letters of Grants - A-B, 1975-1985 (Box 31, Folder 255)
  - Stabilization (Cash Reserve Program) Letters of Grants - C-G, 1975-1985 (Box 31, Folder 256)
  - Stabilization (Cash Reserve Program) Letters of Grants - H-M, 1975-1985 (Box 31, Folder 257)
  - Stabilization (Cash Reserve Program) Letters of Grants - N-O, 1972-1985 (Box 31, Folder 258)
  - Stabilization (Cash Reserve Program) Letters of Grants - P-R, 1977-1987 (Box 31, Folder 259)
  - Stabilization (Cash Reserve Program) Letters of Grants - S, 1977-1987 (Box 32, Folder 260)
  - Stabilization (Cash Reserve Program) Letters of Grants - T-Z, 1977-1987 (Box 32, Folder 261)
  - Economic Survey - Theater - Canadian and Defunct - IV, 1965-1966 (Box 32, Folder 262)
    Folder alternatively titled SAB Site Visits
    Information sheets for:
    Academy Theatre
    Theatre Communications Group - Phoenix Theatre
    TCG Theatre Information Sheet - Lyceum Theatre
    Syracuse Repertory Theatre
    NYSF Public Theater
    New York Shakespeare Festival Public Theater
    Alliance Theatre Company
    American Place Theatre
    Repertory Theatre at Loretto-Hilton Center
    Canadian and Defunct:
    Manitoba Theatre Center
    Stratford Festival
    Defunct:
    Actor's Workshop
    Atlanta Municipal Theater
    Charles Playhouse
    Front Street Theatre
    Pasadena Playhouse
    Stanford Repertory Theatre
    Theatre of the Living Arts
    Theatre Saint Paul
  - Economic Survey - Ballet and Modern Dance, 1971-1973 (Box 32, Folder 263)
    Ballet
    1. New York City Ballet
    2. Ballet Theatre Foundation, Inc.
    3. Joffrey Ballet
    4. Pennsylvania Ballet
    5. National Ballet Society, Inc.
    6. San Francisco Ballet Company
    7. Boston Ballet Company, Inc.
    8. Ballet West
    9. Dance Theatre of Harlem, Inc.
    10. Houston Ballet Foundation
    Modern Dance
    1. Alvin Ailey City Center Dance Theatre
    2. American Ballet Theater Company
    3. Merce Cunningham and Dance Company
    4. Martha Graham Center of Contemporary Dance
    5. Erick Hawkins Dance Company
    6. Murray Louis Dance Company
    7. Alwin Nikolais Dance Theatre
    8. Repertory Dance Theater
    9. Paul Taylor Dance Foundation, Inc.
  - Economic Survey - Theater - $500,000 or Less - III, 1970-1971 (Box 32, Folder 264)
    Actors Theatre of Louisville
    Asolo Theatre
    Barter Theatre
    Center Stage Associate
    Champlain Shakespeare Festival
    Hartford Stage Co.
    Meadow Brook Theatre
    Mummers Theatre
    New Orleans Repertory Theatre
    Stage/West
    Theatre Co. of Boston
    Washington Theatre Club
    Yale Repertory Theatre
  - Economic Survey - Theater - Between $500,000 and $1,000,000 - II, 1970-1971 (Box 32, Folder 265)
    Alley Theater
    Cincinnati Playhouse in the Park
    Cleveland Play House
    Long Wharf Theater
    Milwaukee Repertory Theatre
    Negro Ensemble Company, Inc.
    Seattle Repertory Theatre
    Studio Arena Theater
    Trinity Square Repertory Theatre
  - Economic Survey - Theater - $1,000,000 and Over - I, 1966-1967 (Box 33, Folder 266)
    American Conservatory Theatre
    American Shakespeare Theatre
    Arena Stage
    Goodman Theater (Art Institute of Chicago)
    Guthrie Theatre (Minnesota Theatre Co.)
    Repertory Theatre of Lincoln Center, Inc.
    Taper Forum, Mark
  - Economic Survey - Symphony (Part I), 1970-1971 (Box 33, Folder 267)
    Between $500,000 and $1,000,000
    $2,500,000 and Over
    Between $1,000,000 and $2,500,000
  - Economic Survey - Symphony (Part II), 1970-1971 (Box 33, Folder 268)
    Between $250,000 and $500,000
    $250,000 or Less
  - Economic Survey - Opera, 1970-1971 (Box 33, Folder 269)
    $1,000,000 and Over
- National Arts Stabilization Fund (NASF), 1970-1994; 4
  Marcia Thompson established the National Arts Stabilization Fund (NASF) in 1983 with grants from the Ford Foundation, the Rockefeller Foundation, and the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation. The NASF recognized that most arts organizations lack both the capital resources, and in many cases, the management and planning systems that are essential for the long-term financial health of their organization. The NASF focused on working with local community leaders, local fundraisers, and local arts organizations to fund regional stabilization projects. Thompson served as the president of the NASF from 1983-1991.
  - National Arts Stabilization Fund (NASF) Board, 1976-1993 (Box 33, Folder 270)
  - National Arts Stabilization Fund (NASF) - Executive Summary, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 271)
  - National Arts Stabilization Fund (NASF) - Milwaukee, 1991-1993 (Box 33, Folder 272)
  - Board Members, 1986-1994 (Box 33, Folder 273)
  - National Arts Stabilization Fund (NASF) Board - Time Records, 1990-1993 (Box 55, Folder 457)
    Confidential Material
  - Correspondence and Meeting Materials, 1983-1993 (Box 34, Folder 274)
    Leading Recipients of Foundation Grants
    Pericles, Prince of Tyre, CenterStage, The Head Theater